akersolutions.com 2018-01-27

# Privacy Statement for Aker Solutions | Aker Solutions

The akersolutions.com website is governed in accordance with Norwegian legislation, and the Civil Court of Oslo shall be the legal venue with exclusive jurisdiction over any dispute arising from your use of this website. Aker Solutions is to be considered as data controller and will determine the purposes and means of the processing of personal data submitted online.

## Personal data

Personal data means any information that may be related to an identified or identifiable natural person (the “data subject”). Personal data includes all types of information that are directly or indirectly (that is, used in conjunction with other data) referable to the data subject, such as names, date of birth, addresses, email addresses, telephone numbers, IP addresses etc.

## Collection of personal data

Visitors to this website who order products or services or submit other information to us may be asked to provide personal data in order for Aker Solutions to operate and improve our business and services. If you choose to provide us with personal data, it will be used to provide the information, products or services you request or which we think may be of interest to you or to communicate with you for the same purpose. We collect personal data for purposes of administration and communication, IT and information security, authentication and authorization systems, support systems, collaboration of internal projects and organizational teams and activities. We will process personal data only to the extent required for a specified, explicit and legitimate purpose or for a purpose required by law in places where we operate. The data we collect may be combined with data obtained from other services of Aker Solutions and other companies.

## Use of personal data

We will use personal data for the purpose it is collected for, and we will keep the data only for as long as it is necessary for that purpose. Access to personal data is strictly limited to personnel of Aker Solutions and its controlled subsidiaries and affiliates who have appropriate authorization and a clear business need for that data.

## Cookies

The Aker Solutions website uses cookies to ensure you get the best user experience. Cookies are small text files that are placed on your device to track usage patterns and record preferences. Our cookies do not contain information that can identify persons. If you continue browsing, we assume you accept the use of cookies.

## Sharing of personal data

Personal data will not be shared with third parties except for in circumstances where such sharing is necessary to provide our services. Occasionally we sign up with other companies to work on our behalf, such as for processing and delivery of systems, providing customer support, hosting websites, processing transactions or performing statistical analysis of our services, and we will share necessary information in these cases. Service providers will be permitted to obtain only the personal data they need to deliver their service. We will not disclose your personal data to third parties for the purpose of allowing them to market their products or services to you.

## Transfer of personal data

Aker Solutions has adopted a set of Binding Corporate Rules (BCR) incorporated in the Data Protection Standard to provide a legal basis for authorizing global transfers of data within our group. All Aker Solutions entities and business units are under legal obligation to respect and comply with the rules. The Data Protection Standard is based on the Norwegian Personal Data Act and EU Directive 95/46/EC. The Data Protection Standard allows Aker Solutions to transfer personal data outside the EU, based on our internal data processing practices. The Data Protection Standard includes a set of legally binding data processing rules which grants rights to data subjects. The Data Protection Standard is our tool to protect the privacy of data subjects while at the same time facilitating international global transfers of personal data to the Aker Solutions business units in countries without sufficient data protection legislation. Additional information on the Data Protection Standard of Aker Solutions can be found at http://akersolutions.com/bcr

## Security of processing

We will process your personal data securely and will apply and maintain appropriate technical and organizational measures to protect your personal data against accidental or unlawful destruction or accidental loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access, in particular where the processing involves the transmission of data over a network, and against all other unlawful forms of processing.

## Access to and rectification of personal data

You have the right at any time to access and rectify any information we have collected about you online. To help us keep your personal data updated, we advise you to inform us of any changes or discrepancies. To view and/or edit your personal data, or if you want information on how long we intend to retain your data or have any other questions about your right of access and how to use it, please contact the global data protection officer at Aker Solutions.
